ocgov.com 2006-06-15

# County Of Orange - Privacy Policy

|  |  |   
---  
|   
---  
Privacy Policy  
Scope  
  
The County of Orange maintains this web site as a public service.  The following is the privacy policy regarding this site.  

The Collection and Use of Information  
  
The County of Orange collects information from you under the following two circumstances:  
Information Collected Automatically - Some information is collected from you automatically when you view The County of Orange pages and download information. This may include your Internet Protocol address assigned by your Internet Service Provider, domain name and the type of browser and operating system you used, the date and time you accessed the County of Orange's site, the pages you requested and visited, and the site you linked from to reach the County of Orange. The County of Orange uses this type of information to statistically measure site traffic and to improve the web site. The information is not reviewed on an individual basis but is aggregated with other users for comparison purposes.  
Information Voluntarily Submitted - Additional information may be collected from you if you opt-in or voluntarily provide it in order to:  
fulfill a request for on-line services or choose to personalize the site (register for a County of Orange account).  
The County of Orange uses the information you voluntarily provide to tailor our site to your needs and preferences and to provide the on-line services you are requesting. The type of information we collect will vary with the service being sought and may include your name, address, phone number, e-mail address, social security or federal identification number, credit card number and expiration date, and/or driver license number. If you simply wish to view pages on The County of Orange's site, or conduct transactions, you do not need to personalize the site by registering for an account.  

Cookies  
  
In order to customize your browsing experience, The County of Orange uses "cookies". Cookies allow information to change as you navigate through the pages of a web site. Two types of cookies can be used, "session-only" and "persistent". The County of Orange uses cookies in the following ways:  
If you wish to access information but do not want to personalize the site, The County of Orange uses session-only cookies to reserve some storage on your computer in order to take your query and pass it along to the page that will serve up the information you request. The session-only cookies are erased either during web browser operation or after your web browser is shut down.  
If you wish to conduct on-line transactions but do not want to personalize the site, The County of Orange uses session-only cookies to process your request. The type of information voluntarily submitted to fulfill your request varies by transaction and may include your name, address, phone number, e-mail address, social security or federal identification number, credit card number and expiration date, and/or driver license number.  
If you choose to register with The County of Orange to personalize the site and wish to be remembered, The County of Orange uses permanent cookies that remain on your computer's hard drive as small text files. These permanent cookies allow The County of Orange to recognize you when you return to our site. When you register with The County of Orange, we ask you to identify yourself by your name and email address. This allows The County of Orange to customize the presentation of information for you based upon what you have asked for and/or voluntarily provided during previous visits. The County of Orange only uses permanent cookies that store personal information with the permission of the user.  
If you choose to register with The County of Orange to personalize the site but do not wish to be remembered, The County of Orange uses session cookies that are destroyed when you close your browser.  
The County of Orange has links to other web sites outside of state government. When you link to one of these sites, The County of Orange cannot control their use of cookies and this privacy policy will not apply. Click here to view the The County of Orange Linking Policy.

If you choose to do so, you can configure your browser to notify you when a new cookie is received. You can also prevent your browser from accepting any new cookies, view and delete existing cookies or disable cookies altogether. Click here to link to directions on how to do this.  

Information Sharing and Disclosure  
  
The County of Orange will only send personal information about you to others when:  
we have your consent to share the information; or  
we need to share your information to provide the product or service you have requested; or we are authorized to do so by law (e.g., to respond to subpoenas, court orders, legal process, or to requests pursuant to a statute requiring or permitting disclosure such as the Freedom of Information Act.)  

Editing and Deleting Your Account Information  
  
You will be able to edit your The County of Orange account information and preferences at any time. You may delete your The County of Orange account by accessing the "Update My Profile" button and selecting "Delete Profile"  

Changes to this Privacy Policy  
  
The County of Orange may amend this policy from time to time. The County of Orange will prominently display on this website any substantial change in the way we use your personal information.  

Directions for Controlling Cookies:  
  
Using Internet Explorer to Control Which Cookies You Accept:  
If you are using Internet Explorer 5.0:  
Choose Tools, then  
Internet Options.  
Click the Security tab,  
Click Internet, then Custom Level.  
Scroll down to Cookies and choose one of the two options.  
If you are using Internet Explorer 4.0:  
Choose View, then  
Internet Options.  
Click the Advanced tab,  
Scroll down to the yellow exclamation icon under Security and choose one of the three options to regulate your use of cookies.  
In Internet Explorer 3.0, you can choose View, Options, Advanced and click on the button that says Warn Before Accepting "Cookies."

Using Internet Explorer to View or Delete Cookies You Have Accepted:  
If you're using Internet Explorer 5.0:  
Choose Tools, then  
Internet Options.  
Under the tab General (the default tab)click  
Settings, then  
View Files.  
To delete a cookie, highlight it and delete it.  
If you're using Internet Explorer 4.0  
Choose View, then  
Internet Options.  
Under the tab General (the default tab)click  
Settings, then  
View Files.  
To delete a cookie, highlight it and delete it.  
If you are using Internet Explorer 3.0  
Choose View, then  
Options, then  
Advanced, then  
View Files.  
To delete a cookie, highlight it and delete it.  
Using Netscape to Control Cookies: Netscape bundles all cookies into one file on your hard drive. You'll need to find the file, which it calls Cookie.txt on Windows machines.

If you are using Netscape Communicator 4.0:  
Select "Edit | Preferences..." from the main menu.  
Select "Advanced"  
To enable cookies: Select "Accept all cookies" or "Accept only cookies that get sent back to the originating server"  
To disable cookies: Select "Disable cookie"  
To get a prompt: Check "Warn me before accepting a cookie" and select "Accept all cookies" or "Accept only cookies that get sent back to the originating server"  
Click "OK"  
To delete cookies, locate the file called cookie.txt on your computer at c:program filesnetscapeusersdefault and delete it.  
If you are using Navigator 3.x:  
Select "Options | Network Preferences..." from the main menu.  
Change to the "Protocols" tab.  
Navigator 3.x does not have an option to completely disable accepting cookies. To get a prompt: Check "Accepting a Cookie" under "Show an Alert Before"  
Click "OK"  

|   
---  
|  |   
Privacy[Legal](http://www.ocgov.com/legal.asp "Link - Legal")[ADA](http://www.ocgov.com/ada.asp "Link - ADA") | © 1997 - 2004 All rights reserved
